cyclegear.com 2017-09-28

# Privacy Policy - Cycle Gear

This Privacy Policy ("Privacy Policy") governs the manner in which Cycle Gear, Inc. collects, uses, maintains and discloses information collected from users (each, a "User" or "you") of the www.cyclegear.com website ("Site"). This Privacy Policy applies to the Site and all products and services offered by Cycle Gear.

**Personal Identifiable Information**  
We may collect personal identification information ("PII") from Users in a variety of ways, including, but not limited to, when Users visit our Site, register on the Site, place an order, subscribe to the newsletter, respond to a survey, fill out a form, and in connection with other activities, services, features or resources we make available on our Site. Users may be asked for, as appropriate, name, email address, mailing address, phone number, credit card information. Users may, however, visit our Site anonymously. We will collect PII from Users only if they voluntarily submit such information to us. Users can always refuse to supply PII, except that it may prevent them from engaging in certain Site related activities.

**Non-Personal Identifiable Information**  
We may collect non-personal identification information about Users whenever they interact with our Site. Non-personal identification information may include the browser name, the type of computer and technical information about Users means of connection to our Site, such as the operating system and the Internet service providers utilized and other similar information.

**Web Browser Cookies**  
Cycle Gear uses commonly employed Internet technologies to collect additional information. For example, Cycle Gear uses "cookies" to determine how users reach the Site and to track general usage patterns once a user is on the Site. This information is collected and analyzed in the aggregate in order to improve the function, content, overall appearance, and capability of the Site. "Cookies" are small pieces of information that are transferred by a Site and stored by your Web browser on your computer's hard drive.

Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies; however, you can always choose not to accept a cookie by changing your computer's preferences to refuse cookies or to prompt you to accept each cookie. Although Cycle Gear requires that your Web browser accept cookies to access the Site, Cycle Gear does not store any PII in them. Cycle Gear collects certain technical information from your computer each time you request a page during a visit to the Site. This information is collected from your computer's Web browser to enhance your experience on our Site and may include your IP address, operating system, Web browser software (e.g., Chrome, Internet Explorer, Firefox, or Safari), and screen resolution. In addition, authorized Cycle Gear personnel may update your user profile to accurately reflect any new profile information included in communications received from you. Users may choose to set their web browser to refuse cookies, or to alert them when cookies are being sent. If they do so, note that some parts of the Site may not function properly.

**Mobile Devices**  
Certain mobile devices contain unique identifiers that can be used, for example, to identify the physical location of such devices. Mobile devices also typically transmit caller ID data when used to transmit a telephone call or text message. Cycle Gear may collect, use, transmit, process and maintain unique identifiers, caller ID data, location-based data, and similar information when you rely on mobile devices, in order to improve your experience on the Site. Cycle Gear also may require collection of your mobile phone number in order for you to participate in certain services or features and that number may be associated with such information.

**How We Use Collected Information**  
Cycle Gear may collect and use Users personal information for the following purposes:

**To improve customer service**  
Information you provide helps us respond to your customer service requests and support needs more efficiently.

**To personalize user experience**  
We may use information in the aggregate to understand how our Users as a group use the services and resources provided on our Site.

**To improve our site**  
We may use feedback you provide to improve our products and services.

**To process payments**  
We may use the information Users provide about themselves when placing an order only to provide service to that order. We do not share this information with outside parties except to the extent necessary to provide the service.

**To share your information with third parties**  
We may share or sell information with third parties for marketing or other purposes.

**To send periodic emails**  
We may use the email address to send User information and updates pertaining to their order. It may also be used to respond to their inquiries, questions, and/or other requests. If User decides to opt-in to our mailing list, they will receive emails that may include company news, updates, related product or service information, etc. If at any time the User would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, we include detailed unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of each email or User may contact us via our Site.

**To run a promotion, contest, survey or other site feature**

**To send Users information they agreed to receive about topics we think will be of interest to them**

**How We Protect Your Information**  
We adopt appropriate data collection, storage and processing practices and security measures to protect against unauthorized access, alteration, disclosure or destruction of your personal information, username, password, transaction information and data stored on our Site. Sensitive and private data exchange between the Site and its Users happens over a SSL secured communication channel and is encrypted and protected with digital signatures. Our Site is also in compliance with PCI vulnerability standards in order to create as secure of an environment as possible for Users. The importance of security for all PII associated with our Users is of utmost concern to us. However, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100 percent secure. As a result, we make no representation or warranty as to the security of any information Users transmit to us, or the potential loss, misuse, or alteration of the PII that we collect on our Site. In particular, Cycle Gear cannot be responsible for the actions of any third parties who might receive your PII.

**Sharing Your Personal Information**  
We may use third-party service providers to help us operate our business. We may share your information with these third parties and appropriate companies that offer similar products, taking great care to ensure that your information will be used responsibly. We do not share any personal financial or purchase information, only name and address if applicable. If you would prefer not to have your name and address shared, please send an email to [cs@cyclegear.com](http://cs@cyclegear.com/) with “opt-out” in the subject line and we will not share your information.

**Third-Party Websites**  
Users may find advertising or other content on our Site that link to the sites and services of our partners, suppliers, advertisers, sponsors, licensors and other third parties. We do not control the content or links that appear on these sites and are not responsible for the practices employed by websites linked to or from our Site. Any information you provide to third-party websites will be governed under the terms of each such website's policies. In addition, these sites or services, including their content and links, may be constantly changing. Browsing and interaction on any other website, including websites which have a link to our Site, is subject to that website's own terms and policies.

**Compliance with Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act**  
Protecting the privacy of the very young is especially important. For that reason, we never collect or maintain information at our Site from those we actually know are under 13, and no part of our website is structured to attract anyone under 13.

**Changes to This Privacy Policy**  
Cycle Gear has the discretion to update this privacy policy at any time. When we do, we will revise the updated date at the bottom of this page. We encourage Users to frequently check this page for any changes to stay informed about how we are helping to protect the personal information we collect. You acknowledge and agree that it is your responsibility to review this privacy policy periodically and become aware of modifications.

**Your Acceptance of These Terms**  
By using this site, you signify your acceptance of this policy. If you do not agree to this policy, please do not use our site. Your continued use of the site following the posting of changes to this policy will be deemed your acceptance of those changes.

**Contacting Us**  
If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this site, please contact us at:

Cycle Gear  

4705 Industrial Way Benicia, CA 94510  
1-800-292-5343
